CONTACT INFORMATION Rm 614, Kelvin Building University of Glasgow Glasgow, G12 8QQ United Kingdom Work: +44 (0)14133 08855 Web: www.pauljwright.co.uk Email: paul.wright@glasgow.ac.uk Publication List: SAO/NASA ADS

RESEARCH INTERESTS My interests range from stellar to solar physics; my main interests lie in the heating of the solar atmosphere, including active regions and loops. I have expertise in analysis of data from SDO/AIA, Hinode/EIS, Hinode/XRT, and NuSTAR Solar observations.

EDUCATION

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK

2014 – present (expected 2018)

Ph.D. Solar Physics

Thesis Topic: *The Energetics of Small Flares and Brightenings* Advisers: Dr Iain G. Hannah, Dr Alexander MacKinnon

University of Southampton, Southampton, UK

2010 - 2014

MPhys Astrophysics with a year abroad

First class honours (1:1) Adviser: Professor Malcolm Coe

Harvard University/Harvard-Smithsonian CfA, Cambridge, MA

2013 - 2014

MPhys Astrophysics with a year abroad

Thesis Topic: Superflare Rates of Solar-Like Stars Advisers: Dr Steven H. Saar, Dr Jeremy J. Drake

CURRENT ACADEMIC APPOINTMENT

Affiliate Staff Member, University of Glasgow SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy

2017 – present

 Investigating the non-flaring coronal time-series data for signs of the coronal heating mechanism.

PREVIOUS
ACADEMIC
APPOINTMENTS

Post-Graduate Research Assistant, University of Glasgow

2014 - 2017

SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy

Project: The Energetics of Small Flares and Brightenings

- Analysed observations of the Sun with *NuSTAR*, a telescope not designed for heliophysics. These observations are the most sensitive of their kind and have resulted in numerous, wide-ranging highly-collaborative peer-reviewed publications.
- Analysed non-flaring coronal time-series in order to extract signatures of the coronal heating mechanism. Techniques included Fourier analysis, Wavelet analysis, and Local Intermittency Measure.
- Studied the temperature distribution of the solar atmosphere through the recovery of an ill-posed inverse problem using techniques such as Tikhonov Regularization, Markov-Chain Monte Carlo, and Sparsity.
- This work had coverage by news outlets including The BBC...

Collaborators: Iain Hannah, Alexander MacKinnon

Visiting Researcher, NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC)

2016

Heliophysics Science Division

• Worked on the possibility of implementing DEM maps in the Helioviewer project, and their usefulness as an input for various established analysis techniques.

Collaborators: Nicholeen Viall, Jack Ireland

Research Scholar, Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics (CfA) 2013 – 2014 Solar and Stellar X-Ray Group

- Designed and implemented a sophisticated stellar flare detection routine for long-cadence (30 mins) *Kepler* data.
- This work has had coverage by Science, and The Smithsonian Magazine.

Collaborators: Steven Saar, Søren Meibom, Jeremy Drake, Vinay Kashyap

REFEREED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS	[1] Marsh, A. J., Smith, D. M., Glesener, L. et al 2017. First NuSTAR Limits of Sun Hard X-Ray Transient Events, ApJ (in revision)	on Quiet	
	[2] Wang, J., Simões, P. J. A., Jeffrey, N. L. S. et al 2017. Observations of Reconnection Flows in a Flare on The Solar Disk, ApJL, 847, L1		
	[3] Wright, P. J. , Hannah, I. G., Grefenstette, B. W., et al 2017. Microflare Heating of a Solar Active Region Observed with NuSTAR, Hinode/XRT, and SDO/AIA, ApJ, 844, 132		
	[4] Kuhar, M., Krucker, S., Hannah, I. G., et al 2017. Evidence of Significant Input in the Late Phase of a Solar Flare from NuSTAR X-ray Observation 835, 6		
FIRST AUTHOR PUBLICATIONS IN PREPERATION	[5] Wright, P. J., Hannah, I. G., Viall, N. M., et al		
	[6] Wright, P. J., Saar, S. H., Meibom, S., et al		
Conferences,	Invited Oral Presentations		
WORKSHOPS, &	ISSI Team Meeting: Coronal Nanoflares, Bern, CH	2016	
SCHOOLS	Harvard-Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics, Cambridge, MA, USA	2014	
SCHOOLS		2014	
	Oral/ePoster Presentations		
	Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS), Portland, OR, USA	2017	
	Coronal Loops Workshop VIII, Palermo, Sicily, IT	2017	
	Living with a Star (SDO/LWS) Workshop, Burlington, VT, USA	2016	
	Hinode 10, Nagoya, JP	2016	
	National Astronomy Meeting 2016, Nottingham, UK	2016	
	Hinode 9, Belfast, UK	2015	
	Glasgow-Cambridge Flare Workshop, Glasgow, UK	2015	
	Poster Presentations		
	European Solar Physics Meeting (ESPM), Budapest, HU	2017	
	Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS), Portland, OR, USA	2017	
	Living with a Star (SDO/LWS) Workshop, Burlington, VT, USA	2016	
	Coronal Loops Workshop VII, Cambridge, UK	2015	
	NAM 2015, Llandudno, UK	2015	
	223rd AAS Meeting, National Harbor, MD, USA	2013	
		2011	
	Schools Attended		
	CESRA Radio Summer School 2015, Glasgow, UK	2015	
	STFC Advanced Summer School in Solar Physics, Dundee, UK	2014	
	Conferences/Workshops Attended		
	NuSTAR Heliophysics Workshop (remote participation), Berkeley, CA, USA	2017	
	SUPA Cormack Astronomy Meeting, Edinburgh, UK	2015	
	RAS Discussion Meeting: Results from IRIS, London, UK	2015	
	SUPA Cormack Astronomy Meeting, Edinburgh, UK	2014	
	1st Space Glasgow Research Conference, Glasgow, UK	2014	
AWARDS AND GRANTS TOTAL: £7000	SUPA School of Physics and Astronomy, University of Glasgow		
	Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS) Student Poster Award	2017	
	Solar Physics Division Meeting (SPD/AAS) Studentship Award	2017	
	Coronal Loops Workshop VIII Travel Award	2017	
	National Astronomical Observatory of Japan Travel Award	2016	
	Hinode 9 Travel Award	2015	
	European Space Agency/Cambridge Philosophical Society Travel Award	2015	

AWARDS AND	School of Physics and Astronomy, University of Southampton		
GRANTS (CONT.)	Research Scholarship 2013		
CRAINTS (CONT.)	Summer Studentship Grant 2013		
T			
TEACHING	University of Glasgow		
	Astronomy 1 Tutorial Demonstrator 2016 - 2017 Supervised students, and marked first year astronomy problem sets.		
	Physics Pre-University Summer School 2015 Engaged students in various physics experiments and marked assignments.		
	Astronomy 3/4 (Honours) Laboratory Demonstrator 2015 - 2016		
	Demonstrated, supervised, and marked a number of final-year research projects cov-		
	ering topics such as asteroid light curves, and solar limb darkening.		
Memberships	NuSTAR Heliophysics Working Group, Member 2015 – present		
WEWELLSTIN S	International Space Science Institute (ISSI), Young Scientist Member 2015 – present		
	Member of Paola Testa's ISSI Team: New Diagnostics of Particle Acceleration in Solar		
	Coronal Nanoflares from Chromospheric Observations and Modeling		
	Royal Astronomical Society , RAS Fellow 2014 – present		
COMMUNITY	Nature Communications, Reviewer 2017 – present		
Involvement	CESRA Radio Summer School, Volunteer Organiser 2015		
SCIENTIFIC	Glasgow Science Centre, Demonstrator 2016		
OUTREACH	British Science Week, Demonstrator 2016		
OUTKEACH	Institute of Physics: Women and Girls in Science, Demonstrator 2016		
	Scottish Television (STV), Guest Presenter 2015		
	World Wide Telescope, Ambassador 2013 – 2014		
	BBC Stargazing Live, Demonstrator 2013		
	So'ton Astrodome, Demonstrator 2012		
	BBC Bang Goes The Theory Roadshow , Demonstrator 2012		
	UK Solar Physics (UKSP) Nuggets, concise, easy-to-read science articles		
	84. The first NuSTAR microflare 2017		
	Hinode/XRT Picture of the Week (XPOW)		
	The First Microflare Observations with Hinode/XRT & NuSTAR 2017		
PERSONAL PROJECTS	ColourBlind, A repository for colour-blind-friendly colour tables. Citations: 1		
PROFESSIONAL	Coursera, Inc. (MOOC Platform)		
DEVELOPMENT	Using Coursera.org, a massive open online course (MOOC) platform, to take specializa-		
	tions (sets of multiple courses) offered by accredited universities to further develop skills		
	and understanding in a wide range of computer science applications.		
	Data Science , Johns Hopkins University 2017 – present		
	Nine-course (plus capstone) introduction to data science.		
	Mastering Software Development in R , Johns Hopkins University 2017 – present Four-course (plus capstone) specialization providing riguourous training in the R		
	language.		
	Statistics with R , Duke University 2017 – present		
	Four-course (plus capstone) specialization providing further training in the R lan-		
	guage with emphasis on statistics.		

PROFESSIONAL
DEVELOPMENT
(CONT.)

Big Data, UC San Diego

2017 – present

Five-course (plus capstone) introduction to big data using Hadoop with MapReduce, Spark, Pig and Hive.

Machine Learning, University of Washington

2017 - present

Three-course (plus capstone) introduction to Machine Learning.

Graphic Design, CalArts

2017 - present

Four-course (plus capstone) introduction the fundamental skills required to make sophisticated graphic design.

edx, Inc. (MOOC Platform)

Introduction to Computer Science (CS50x), Harvard University 2017 – present An introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science and the art of programming including languages such as C, and SQL.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Computing: C, Python, R (caret, ggplot2, knitr), SQL, CRAN, IDL, LTEX, git, GitHub, Hadoop (MapReduce, Spark, Pig, Hive), Linux/Unix, Mac OSX, Microsoft Windows, Bash, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Keynote, Wordpress, Shiny, GoogleVis, and Plotly, HTML, CSS, Javascript

General: Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Interdisciplinary Collaboration, Public Speaking, Statistics, Teaching, Writing (Technical & Lay)

MORE Information

More information and auxiliary documents can be found at http://www.pauljwright.co.uk, on ResearchGate, and GitHub.